Devendhar Mandala

devendharmandala05@gmail.com | Arlington, TX | +1 (682) 862-8145

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/devendhar-mandala | GitHub: https://github.com/DevendharMandala

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Java Developer with a master's degree in computer science. Demonstrated expertise in full-stack development, Java, Spring Boot, Python, JavaScript, Angular, and React. Committed to delivering top-quality solutions that drive exceptional user experiences and propel business growth.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science (GPA: 3.8/4.0)

May 2023

The University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, Texas

Courses: Data Bases, Java Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Data Mining, Distributed Systems, Web Data Management]

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering (GPA: 3.5/4.0)

May 2020

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad

Hyderabad, India

[Courses: Object oriented programming (Java), C programming, Operating Systems, Databases, Web Technologies, JSP, HTML, CSS, Software Development]

SKILLS

Programming Languages : Java, C, C#

Web Technologies : HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React

: Spring boot, Maven, Hibernate Frameworks : MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle **Database Technologies**

Cloud Technologies : AWS

Software : GIT, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, GitHub, JIRA

Soft Skills : Teamwork, Communication, Leadership, Time Management, Flexibility

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst, Sensen - Hyderabad, India

Mar 2021 -June 2021

- Extracted Vehicle license plate information and other parts of vehicle by using image processing and OCR on Chicago traffic dataset improved its accuracy by 41%. Followed agile development process.
- Developed a predictive model that segregates the vehicles and their parts based on their shape for effective time management.
- Generated the dashboard to detect and analyze the outlier data and identify the ideal business parameters using logical functions.

Software Engineer, Shris Infotech Pvt. Ltd – Hyderabad, India

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Created a dashboard that provides an overall view of the seller's data including the inventory, sales and monthly revenues.
- Built an Angular JS based UI tool which provided recommendations based on the inventory thereby increasing sales of supermarket.
- Documented several public facing endpoints using open API specification making the API contracts publicly visible to the sellers.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

On Campus Student Market (Java, SQL, Angular)

Fall 2022

- Developed a web application which helps students to trade products with their peers and allows them to make an advertisement. Implemented servlets, multi- threading and Exception handling using core java in this project and also implemented SDLC process.
- Lung Cancer Detection using Computer Vision with CNN (Python, Machine Learning)

- Designed and implemented a state-of-the-art Deep Learning Model to detect malignancy in Lung Cancer, leveraging the IQ-OTHNCCD dataset and achieving an impressive accuracy of 95.48%. and testing errors to below 10% of the classification model's performance.
- Drowsiness Detection by Using Convolutional Neural Networks (Python, Machine Learning).

Spring 2022

- Created a detection System that identifies the key aspects of the drowsiness and sends an alert within 0.16 nano seconds by utilizing image detection and Convolutional Neural Network algorithms and increased efficiency up to 40%.
- **Detection of Cyberbullying in Social Networks** (*Python, Machine Learning, HTML*)

- Built a Web Interface that detects the bullying content in social media by modelling the text with using the machine learning algorithms and increase the efficiency by 35% and added an option to report to the concern authorities once the bullying content reaches its limit.
- **EAMCET Mock Counselling (Java, SQL, HTML).**

- Built a Web Interface that helps future aspirants of the higher education to find the better University based on their entrance exam score. It allows student to university website and shows the direction from their respective location.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERIFICATES

- Awarded the esteemed "Lonestar Scholarship" by UTA.
- Secured "Second place" out of 500 in entrepreneurship hackathon "EXCITE" conducted by JHUB.
- Volunteered for Child and Women safety Hackathon conducted by ACE Engineering College.
- Member of National Service Scheme (NSS) from December 2018- December 2019.
- Participated in coding contests conducted by Ace Engineering college like FACEIT, RACEIT and achieved 2nd place in RACEIT.
- "Captain" of the "Kabaddi Sport team" at ACE Engineering College from August 2017- December 2019.